Register of the Wade H. Haislip Papers, 1941-1972.
Hoover Institution Archives
Wade H. Haislip Papers
1941-1972
74061
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 envelope, 1 album box, memorabilia (3.7 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, orders, awards, citations, photographs, clippings, and printed matter, relating to American military activities in the European Theater during World War II, and to postwar administration of the Army.
Haislip, Wade H. (Wade Hampton), 1889-1971.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note.
1889, December 22 Born, Woodstock, Virginia
1912 B.S., U.S.M.A., West Point, N.Y.
1917-1918 Assigned to Third Division
1927 Graduate, Ecole Superieure de Guerre
1942 Promoted to Major General
1943-1945 Commanding General of XV Corps
1945 President of the Secretary of War's Personnel Board
1949 Promoted to General; Vice Chief of Staff of the Army
United States. Army--Officers.; United States. Army. Army, 7th.; United States. Army. Corps, XV.; United States--Armed Forces.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Western.; World War, 1939-1945.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1945-1968
  - Chronological file, letters sent and received, 1944-1945. Correspondence includes among others: (Box 1)
    - Bemberg, Madame
    - Bradley, General Omar
    - Brooke, Sir Basil
    - Clark, General Mark W.
    - Coulter, Major General John B.
    - Devers, General Jacob L.
    - Dietrich, Marlene
    - Eisenhower, General Dwight D.
    - Kellogg, Colonel Hamilton H.
    - Leclerc, General Jacques-Phillipe (France)
    - Lee, Lieutenant General Robert M.
    - Littlejohn, General Robert M.
    - Lovett, Brigadier General Ralph B.
    - Marshall, General George C.
    - McNair, Lieutenant General Lesley J.
    - Pancake, William C.
    - Patton, Lieutenant General George S.
    - Rixey, Brigadier General George F.
    - Wheeler, Lieutenant General Raymond A.
    - Wilson, General Arthur
    - Wyman, General William C.
  - Alphabetical file, 1945-1968
    - Ditzen, Lowell R.
    - Maule, Henry R.
    - Mercedes-Benz of North America, Inc.
    - Nichols, Lee
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1945-1946
  - "To Officers and Men of XV Corps, Commemorating the Capture of Nurnberg," 21 April, 1945 (Box 1)
  - "General Eisenhower,'s Life."
- SUBJECT FILE, 1941-1972
  - "Army Green Uniform," S. J. Kennedy and Alice Park (Box 1)
  - "Battle of National Redoubt," R. E. Jenkins, 1946
  - Biographical file
  - Churchill, Winston, greets Army ahd Navy officers, 1946
  - Citations and awards
  - L'Ecole Superieure De Guerre, alumni bulletin, 1965
  - XV Corps in France
  - XV Corps in World War II
  - Memorabilia
  - News clipping (Box 2)
  - Orders
    - General orders, 1941-1945
    - Special orders, combat reports, XV Corps, 1944-1945
  - Personnel security questionnaire
  - President's Advisory Committee on Government Organization, notebook containing proposals, 1953
  - United States Military Academy report, "Assembly," 1972
  - United States War Department General Staff, file
  - West, O. B., "Atlantic Wall to Siegfried Line, A Study In Command," military operations and strategic matters within the Western Theater of Operations, World War II, and descriptions of the German Operations, World War II, and descriptions of the German Commanders involved, includes Generals: Blumentritt; von Buttlar; von Rundstedt; Speidel; and Zimmermann
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - United States Army, 100th Infantry Division in the European Theater of Operations (Box on shelf)
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - 12 prints of General Wade H. Haislip in group and individual photos, including 1 print of nine former Seventh Army Commanders taken at Heidelberg, Germany, 1968; 1 group photo of General Haislip with Generals George S. Patton and Jacques-Phillipe Leclerc, circa 1945. (Envelope A)
  - Photo album presented to General Haislip in Commemoration of the visit of the former Seventh Army Commanders to the Daimler-Benz Aktiengesellschaft in Stuttgart, Germany, November 11-13, 1968 (Album fB)